Annika Neumann

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



07849 524 295



annika1983neumann@gmail.com



github.com/AnnikaNeumann



linkedin.com/in/annika-neumann-422b98232



annikaneumann.github.io

EDUCATION

CODECLAN EDINBURGH

February 2022 – June 2022 CodeClan, Edinburgh – Professional Software Development Course

CodeClan is a digital skills academy providing a 16-week SQA Level 8 accredited

Professional Software Development course, teaching the fundamentals of software development using agile methodologies, test-driven development, and object-oriented programming.

The course develops the following technologies and skills:

- SOLID principles
- RESTful workflows
- Pair/mob programming; development projects (solo, pair, group)
- GitHub
- Python, Flask, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, React,
 Node, Java, Spring
- SQL and MongoDB

PROFILE

An eager Junior Software Developer who has taken the CodeClan journey to change career and be challenged by a variety of new opportunities.

For the past 20 years I've had different roles within the health care sector and administration of Germany, Switzerland and the UK.

These provided me with great interpersonal skills and the discipline to work within deadlines, these roles also required creative thinking and quick problem solving. I am looking for a role where I can develop my FrontEnd skills and take them to the next level.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Captstone Project - BeyondTravelling

https://github.com/elicodes89/BeyondTravelling

An app to search for wheelchair and deaf friendly accommodation in the UK. We teamed up with a Qualified British Sign Language Interpreter to record short sentences, eg. "Hotel has 24 hour reception" or "Hotel has vibrating fire alarm", as well as an intro video about our app and and a video for a deaf friendly hotel in Dublin.

Built with JavaScript, React, Css, Java and Spring

Educational App - Trivia Quiz

github.com/AnnikaNeumann/trivia_js_project

A Quiz App which includes an open source API. You can interact and play the theme song, play a quiz and select from a variety of categories and difficulty levels. Your scores are being tracked by using a database and then displayed at the end of your game.

Built with JavaScript, React, Css, MongoDb and Express

Annika Neumann JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

DEAF ACTION EDINBURGH

February 2018 - June 2021 SQA Level 1 and 2 -British Sign Language (SCQF 5)

APPRENTICESHIP "MANAGEMENT ASSISTANT FOR HEALTHCARE"

2003 - 2006

Evangelisches Altenwerk Loerrach e.V. Germany

TECH VOLUNTEER

since August 2023

Volunteering with the UK Charity
Organisation AbilityNet to support older
people and people with disabilities to
access technology at home

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- German (fluent)
- English (fluent)
- British Sign Language (Level 2)

OTHER SKILLS

- Capable to work in a fast pace environment
- Strong ability to work within a team as well on initiative to determine priorities within the workload for each day
- Excellent Communication skills
- Organised
- Time management
- Empathic
- Adaptive

Breaking Bad App

github.com/AnnikaNeumann/W7Hw_BreakingBad_React

An app which includes an open source API to fetch data about the show's characters. You can look at 25 characters and click on the button to get more information on the actual actors.

Built with Javascript, React and Css.

EXPERIENCE

JUNIOR TALEND ENGINEER

Computershare August 2022 to present

- Being responsible for the problem solving of Jira tickets with support of our Mid-level Talend Engineer.
- Attending and participating in daily Stand Ups, Backlog and Retrospective meetings and Sprint Planning.
- On a daily basis using the Talend ETL tool in combination with correct SQL queries and Oracle databases to deliver accurate statements holding information about client' share plans.
- Being pro-active about creating new documentation and participating in the Computershare Academy for further development and education about Oracle, Java and FrontEnd.
- Achievements: me and the other 2 Developers successfully migrated all 20 Talend jobs to a new version of Talend, adding additional functionality to implement a barcode tag to the xml for North America in combination with DDL and testing.

RESOURCE COORDINATOR

Interpretation & Translation Service NHS Lothian September 2017 - February 2022

- Liaising with interpreters as well as clinics regarding any appointment issues.
- Communicating with external agencies as well as charity organisations in case of availability issues.
- Processing Interpreter's payments including travel expenses
- Being the main contact for any British Sign Language (BSL) requests, in collaboration with the deaf-led organisation.
- Continued assistance with developing the day to day processes

Annika Neumann JUNIOR SOFTWARE

PERSONAL INTERESTS

DEVELOPER

- My own cat and providing a foster home to cats in need
- British Sign Language
- Undertaking deque University courses about Accessibility
- Attending Comic / Star Trek Conventions
- Touring with my Vespa
- Being involved in environmental activities
 such as Foodsharing

Achievements:

To make sure that hearing impaired patients can request a qualified BSL Interpreter for their NHS related appointments, I created non-clinical alerts for around 600 patient's profiles. A flashing triangle shows up when the patient's profile is clicked on, which helps clinical staff to recognise immediately if the patient needs an Interpreter.

VARIOUS ADMINISTRATIVE ROLES BETWEEN MARCH 2014 AND JULY 2017

Royal Edinburgh Hospital -Edinburgh Behavioural Support Service Imamed Radiologie Nordwest - Basel, Switzerland

- First point of contact and providing administrative support to visiting consultants of care homes.
- Maintaining the team caseloads, outpatient waiting lists and consultant's diary
- First point of contact to patients, hospitals and GP's
- Reception of patients and registering them, maintaining their records under GDPR, preparing them for ultrasound assessments.
- Appointment coordination for all three location
- Administrative tasks including electronic dispatch of images and documents.